A Guide to the Gertrude E. Perlmann papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA189
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Manuscript materials
  - L.G. Longsworth, 1945 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Typescript communication dated 1945 Mar 26 to G.E. Perlmann on "moving boundary theory - proteins" [Description from file folder].
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1945 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    Ionic strength experiments ß-lactoglobulin [Description from file folder].
    [See related paper by Perlmann and Kaufman #10 in bibliography].
    Typescript drafts; figures; 1945, 1947 laboratory notes; working materials; copy 1945 Mar 26.
    Longsworth/Perlmann communication.
  - G.E. Perlmann and D. Kaufman, 1945 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    The effect of ionic strength and protein concentration in the electrophoretic analysis of human plasma.
    J Am Chem Soc 67, 638-641.
    Figures only.
  - G.E. Perlmann and D. Kaufman, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    Electrophoretic distribution of proteins in serum, plasma and synovial fluid of patients with rheumatoid arthritis.
    J Clin Inv 25, 931.
    Typescript drafts.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1948 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    Electrophoretic behaviour of modified ovalbumins.
    Nature 161, 720.
    Correspondence; typescript draft; figures.
  - G.E. Perlmann and L.G. Longsworth, 1948 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    The specific refractive increment of some purified proteins.
    J Am Chem Soc 70, 2719-2724.
    Typescript draft; figures; working figures.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    The electrophoretic properties of plakalbumin.
    J Am Chem Soc 71, 1146-1149.
    Correspondence; typescript draft; figures; working table.
  - G.E. Perlmann and D. Kaufman, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    The effect of acetic acid on the stability of serum proteins.
    J Biol Chem 179, 133-137.
    Correspondence; typescript draft; figures; working materials.
  - W.F. Goebel and G.E. Perlmann, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    The effect of lithium periodate on crystalline bovine serum albumin.
    J Exp Med 89, 479-489.
    Typescript draft; figures.
  - M.W. Ropes, D. Kaufman and G.E. Perlmann, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    Variations in the electrophoretic pattern of synovial fluid in articular disease.
    J Clin Inv 28, 807.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    Phosphorus content of ovalbumin and of some products of its enzymatic degradation.
    Nature 164, 961.
    Correspondence; typescript draft.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    Enzymatic dephosphorylation of ovalbumin and plakalbumin.
    Nature 166, 870.
  - G.E. Perlmann, I. Tamm and F.L. Horsfall, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    An electrophoretic examination of a urinary mucoprotein which reacts with various viruses.
    J Exp Med 95, 99-104.
    Correspondence; typescript draft; figures;.
    Tamm and Horsfall published paper.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    JGP 35, 711-726.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    Alkali denaturation of ovalbumin.
    Correspondence; typescript draft; laboratory notes; published papers by others.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    Enzymatic dephosphorylation of casein.
    J Am Chem Soc 74, 3191.
    Correspondence; referees reports; typescript draft.
  - R.C. Lancefield and G.E. Perlmann, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    Preparation and properties of type-specific M antigen isolated from a group A type 1 hemolytic streptococcus.
    J Exp Med 96, 71-82.
  - R.C. Lancefield and G.E. Perlmann, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    Preparation and properties of a protein (R antigen) occurring in streptococci of group A type 28 and in certain streptococci of other serological groups.
    J Exp Med 96, 83-97.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1952 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    The phosphorus in pepsin and pepsinogen.
    J Am Chem Soc 74, 6308.
  - M.W. Ropes, G.E. Perlmann, D. Kaufman and W. Bauer, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    The Electrophoretic distribution of proteins in plasma in rheumatoid arthritis.
    J Clin Inv 33, 311-318.
  - G.E. Perlmann, M.W. Ropes, D. Kaufman and W. Bauer, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    The electrophoretic patterns of proteins in synovial fluid and serum in rheumatoid arthritis.
    J Clin Inv 33, 319-325.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    Formation of enzymatically active dialyzable fragments during autodigestion of pepsin.
    Nature 173, 406.
    Correspondence; typescript drafts.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Phosphodiester linkages in proteins.
    B & B Acta 13, 452-453.
  - Jytte Muus, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    The amino acid composition of human salivary gland.
    J Am Chem Soc [Publication information from file folder].
    [This work carried out in G.E. Perlmann laboratory].
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    The phosphorus linkages in casein.
    Nature 174, 273.
  - J.L. Oncley, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    Preliminary experiments on phosphorus linkages in β-lipoprotein. [Description from file folder].
    Handwritten laboratory notes.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    The nature of phosphorus linkages in phosphoproteins.
    Advances in Protein Chemistry 10, 1-30.
    Correspondence; galley proof with corrections; typescript draft with corrections; figures.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    Observations on the effect of urea on crystalline pepsin.
    Arch Biochem Biophys 65, 210-217.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    Enzymic dephosphorylation of pepsin and pepsinogen,.
    JGP 41, 441-450.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    The effect of alkali on the ultraviolet absorption of ovalbumin.
    Bull Soc Chim Biol 40, 2119-2123.
    Correspondence; galley proof; typescript drafts; figures.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    Article on "Fritz A. Lipmann. ".
    Encyclopedia Britannica.
    Correspondence; typescript draft with corrections; workine material.
    [Not included in bibliography].
  - O.O. Blumenfeld and G.E. Perlmann, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    The amino acid composition of crystalline pepsin.
    JGP 42, 553-561.
    Correspondence; galley proof with corrections; typescript draft; figures.
  - O.O. Blumenfeld and G.E. Perlmann, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    Ultraviolet difference spectra of pepsin.
    JGP 42, 563-570.
    Correspondence; galley proof; typescript draft; figures.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    Effect of solvents and of temperature on the optical rotatory properties of pepsin.
    PNAS 45, 915-922.
    Correspondence; galley proof with corrections; typescript drafts.
  - O.O. Blumenfeld, J. Leonis and G.E. Perlmann, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    The effect of guanidine hydrochloride on crystalline pepsin.
    J Biol Chem 25, 379-382.
    Correspondence; galley proof. with corrections; typescript draft; figures; working material.
  - G.E. Perlmann and R. Diringer, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    The structure of proteins.
    Ann Rev Biochem 29, 151-182.
    Correspondence; typescript draft; figure.
  - O.O. Blumenfeld and G.E. Perlmann, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    The disulfide linkages of crystalline pepsin.
    J Biol Chem 236, 2472-2476.
  - G.E. Perlmann and W.F. Harrington, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    Dependence of the optical rotatory properties of pepsinogen on solvent and temperature.
    B & B Acta 54, 606-608.
  - G.E. Perlmann and E. Katchalski, 1962 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    Conformation of poly-l-methionine and some of its derivatives in solution.
    J Am Chem Soc 84, 452-457.
    Correspondence includes Blout (referee) comments on ms; typescript drafts; figures; working material.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1962 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    Book review of "Medical and Biological Research in Israel" edited by M. Prywes.
    Arch Biochem Biophys 98, 532.
    Correspondence; galley proof; typescript draft.
  - R. Arnon and G.E. Perlmann, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    The amino acid composition of chromatographically purified pepsinogen.
    J Biol Chem 238, 653-656.
    Correspondence; galley proof with corrections; typescript draft;.
    reprint of Blumenfeld/Perlmann earlier published paper.
  - R. Arnon and G.E. Perlmann, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    Relation of immunological and enzymic properties to structural modifications of pepsinogen.
    J Biol Chem 238, 963-968.
    Correspondence includes 2 referees comments on ms; galley proof; typescript draft; figures.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    The optical rotatory properties of pepsinogen.
    J Mol Biol 6, 452-464.
    Correspondence includes 2 referees comments on ms; typescript draft with corrections; figures; working material.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1964 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Phenolic hydroxyl ionization in pepsinogen.
    J Biol Chem 239, 3762-3766.
    Correspondence; typescript draft with corrections; galley proof with corrections; working material.
  - S.E. Allerton and G.E. Perlmann, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Chemical characterization of the phosphoprotein phosvitin.
    J Biol Chem 240, 3892-3898.
    Correspondence includes S. Moore comments on ms; typescript drafts with corrections; galley proof with corrections; working material.
  - P.V. Koehn, A.B. Oestreicher and G.E. Perlmann, 1966[?] (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Structural studies on pepsinogen and pepsin.
    The amino acid sequences of tryptic peptide from pepsinogen.
    Typescript draft; Perham and Jones; Dopheide, Moore and Stein typescript mss.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    Acetylation of pepsin and pepsinogen.
    J Biol Chem 241, 153-157.
    Correspondence; typescript draft; figures; printer's proof.
  - G.E. Perlmann and S.E. Allerton, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    Optical rotatory dispersion of phosvitin.
    Nature 211, 1089-1090.
    Correspondence includes referees comments on ms; typescript drafts; figure; galley proof with corrections.
  - E.B. Ong, Y. Tsang and G.E. Perlmann, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    The action of water-insoluble trypsin derivatives on pepsinogen.
    J Biol Chem 241, 5661-5666.
    Correspondence; typescript draft with corrections; figures; galley proof.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    On protein structure.
    In: N.O. Kaplan and E.P. Kennedy eds.
    Current Aspects of Biochemical Energetics.
    New York, Academic Press pp. 265-272.
    (F. Lipmann Dedicatory volume).
    Correspondence; typescript draft; figures; galley proof; F. Lipmann photographs with unidentified others.
  - S.N. Timasheff, R. Townend and G.E. Perlmann, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    The circular dichroism of phosvitin.
    J Biol Chem 242, 2290-2292.
    Correspondence; typescript draft; working ms with corrections.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    Optical rotatory properties of succinylpepsinogen. [Abstract] International Congress Biochem, 7th, Tokyo, 1967.
    Abstracts. A-48, p. 590 Typescript draft of abstract.
    [Not listed in Perlmann bibliography].
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    Conformation of pepsin and pepsinogen.
    In: Ordered Fluids and Liquid Crystals.
    1st, Atlantic City, 1965: Washington, D.C. American Chemical Society, 1967 pp. 268-281 (Advances in Chemistry series 63).
    Correspondence includes referees comments on ms.; typescript draft; figures.
  - A.D. Gounaris and G.E. Perlmann, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    Succinylation of pepsinogen.
    J Biol Chem 242, 2739-2745.
    Correspondence; galley proof; typescript draft with working materials; figures.
  - A.B. Oestreicher and G.E. Perlmann, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    Structural studies on pepsinogen and pepsin, Tryptic digests of pepsinogen and pepsin.
    B and B Acta 140, 319-328.
    Correspondence; typescript draft with working materials.
  - E.B. Ong and G.E. Perlmann, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Specific inactivation of pepsin by benzyloxy-carbonyl-l-phenylalanyldiazomethane.
    Nature 215, 1492-1494.
    Correspondence; typescript drafts; figures.
  - G.E. Perlmann, A. Oplatka and A. Katchalsky, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    Potentiometric titration and conformational change in pepsinogen.
    J Biol Chem 242, 5163-5167.
    Correspondence includes referees comments on ms; typescript drafts with corrections; figures; working material.
  - S. Rimon and G.E. Perlmann, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    Carbamylation of pepsinogen and pepsin.
    J Biol Chem 243, 3566-3572.
    Correspondence; corrected galley proof; typescript draft with corrections; figures; working material.
  - P.V. Koehn and G.E. Perlmann, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    The amino acid sequences of tryptic peptides from porcine pepsinogen.
    J Biol Chem 243, 6099-6103.
    Correspondence includes items on Ong/Perlmann ms #71 in bibliography; corrected galley proof; typescript draft with corrections; figures.
    Includes typescript of P.V. Koehn ms. with correspondence. and corrections by G.E. Perlmann and S. Moore.
  - E.B. One and G.E. Perlmann, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    The amino-terminal sequence of porcine pepsinogen.
    J Biol Chem 243, 6104-6109.
    [Correspondence on this ms. included with Koehn/Perlmann folder #70 in bibliography].
    Corrected galley proof, typescript drafts with corrections; figures.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    Articles on: Albumin; Glutelin; Peptide; Prolamine; Protein; Protein fibrous; Protein globular.
    In: McGraw-Hill Encyclopedia of Science and Technology.
    Correspondence; photocopied drafts for all subjects.
  - K. Grizzutti and G.E. Perlmann, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    Optical rotatory dispersion and circular dichroism of pepsinogen, carbamylpepsinogen and succinylpepsinogen.
    J Biol Chem 244, 1764-1771.
    Correspondence includes referee comments corrected galley proof; typescript draft with corrections; figures.
  - K. Grizzuti and G.E. Perlmann, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    Conformation of the phosphoprotein phosvitin.
    J Biol Chem 245, 2573-2578.
    Correspondence; corrected galley proof; typescript drafts with corrections; figures.
  - Y. Nakagawa and G.E. Perlmann, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    Reduction and reoxidation of pepsinogen and pepsin.
    Arch Biochem Biophys 140, 464-473.
    Correspondence includes reviewer's comments; typescript draft; figures; working material.
  - G.E. Perlmann and K. Grizzuti, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Conformational transition of the phosphoprotein phosvitin. Random conformation → βstructure.
    Biochemistry 10, 258-264.
    Correspondence includes reviewers comments; corrected galley proof; typescript draft; figures; working material.
  - R. Shainkin and G.E. Perlmann, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Phosvitin, a phosphoglycoprotein. I. Isolation and characterization of a glycopeptide from phosvitin.
    J Biol Chem 246, 2278-2284.
    Correspondence includes reviewers comments; corrected galley proof; typescript draft with corrections; figures; working material.
  - Y. Nakagawa and G.E. Perlmann, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    Disulfide bonds of pepsinogen and pepsin: Identification of the disulfide bonds which can be reversibly reduced and reoxidized.
    Arch Biochem Biophys 144, 59-65.
    Correspondence includes reviewer's comments; typescript draft; figures.
  - R. Shainkin and G.E. Perlmann, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    Phosvitin, a phosphoglycoprotein: composition and partial structure of carbohydrate moiety.
    Arch Biochem Biophys 145, 693-700.
    Correspondence includes referees comments; corrected galley proof; typescript drafts; figures.
  - U. Muller-Eberhard and K. Grizzuti, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    Conformational studies on human rabbit plasma hemopexin and on the effect of ligands on the rabbit heme-hemopexin complex.
    [Work reported in this paper supported in part by G.E. Perlmann grand].
    [Internal evidence indicates published in Biochemistry?].
  - G.E. Perlmann and K. Grizzuti, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    Complexes of phosvitin with poly-l-lysine and protamine. Conformational analysis.
    Biochemistry 10, 4168-4176.
    Correspondence includes reviewers comments and Perlmann holograph; corrected galley proof ;typescript draft with corrections ;figures.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    Articles on: Prolamine p. 4.
    Protein pp. 34-39.
    Protein, fibrous p. 39.
    Protein, globular pp. 39-40.
    Glutelin p. 246.
    Albumin p. 256.
    In: Mc-Graw-Hill Encyclopedia of Science and Technology. 3rd Edition.
    Correspondence; tear sheets for all subjects with corrections.
    [Not listed in bibliography].
  - R.C. Wong, Y. Nakagawa and G.E. Perlmann, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    Studies on the nature of the inhibition by gossypol of the transformation of pepsinogen to pepsin.
    Correspondence; corrected galley proof; typescript draft; figures.
  - Y. Nakagawa and G.E. Perlmann, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    Modification of lysine residues of pepsinogen with decarboxylic anhydrides.
    Arch Biochem Biophys 149, 476-483.
  - W. Traub and G.E. Perlmann, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    An x-ray study of phosvitin, the phosphoglycoprotein of hen's egg yolk.
    Israel J Chem 10, 655-658.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    Potentiometric titrations and conformational change.
    In: Hirs, C.H.W. and Timashell, S.N. eds. Methods in Enzymology, v. 26: Enzyme structure part C. New York, Academic Press, pp. 413-423.
    Duplicated material from volume editors to contributors; correspondence; corrected galley proof; typescript draft; figures.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    Book review of "ORD and CD in Chemistry and Biochemistry" by Pierre Crabbe.
    Analytical Chemistry, December (?).
    Correspondence; typescript draft of review [Not listed in bibliography].
  - G.E. Perlmann and G.A. Kerwar, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    Conformational change of pepsin induced by its substrate N-acetyl-L-phenylalanyl-1-3, 5 - diiodotyrosine.
    Arch Biochem Biophys 157, 145-147.
    Correspondence includes reviewers comments; corrected galley proof; typescript draft with corrections; figures; published papers by others used as background material.
  - G.E. Perlmann, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    Phosvitin, a phosphoglycoprotein.
    Israel J Chem 11, 393-405.
    (Published in memory of Aharon Katzir-Katchalsky).
    Correspondence includes referee comments; corrected galley proof; typescript draft; figures.
  - T.H. Finlay, E.D. Dharmgrongartanna and G.E. Perlmann, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Mechanism of the gossypol inactivation of pepsinogen.
    J Biol Chem 248, 4827-4833.
  - K. Grizzuti and G.E. Perlmann, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    The binding of magnesium and calcium ions to the phosphoglycoprotein phosvitin.
    Biochemistry 12, 4399-4403.
    Correspondence includes reviewers comments; corrected galley proof; typescript drafts; figures.
  - U. Marchaim, R.M. Bhatnaga, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    Elevated cyclic AMP levels in chemically induced mouse librosarcoma and their response to dibutyrl cyclic AMP and theophylline,.
    npi [Internal evidence indicates ms rejected by Nature].
    Duplicated copy correspondence; typescript drafts.
  - F. Gaskin, G.E. Perlmann and N.P. Printz, 1974? (Box 26, Folder 4)
    See correspondence. under: Printz, N.P. Box no. 8.
    Ethanol-induced conformational change in pepsinogen.
    Typescript draft with corrections; working material.
- "Methods in Enzymology," Vol. XIX. (Box 27)
  "Proteolytic Enzymes," 1970 edited by G.E. Perlmann and L. Lorand in the Colwick-Kaplan series of Methods in Enzymology
  - Miscellaneous (Box 27, Folder 1)
    Includes correspondence; duplicated editorial instructions; preface: sample of letters to contributors and instruction for organization of chapters; also listing of contributors; addresses; chapter headings; table of contents; publishers advertising leaflets; review of Vol. XIX Proteolytic Enzymes.
  - Correspondence with Academic Press, 1967-1971 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with S.P. Colowick, N.O. Kaplan, Laszlo Lorand (Box 27, Folder 3)
    Includes Colowick/Kaplan publication congratulations.
    Arranged in alphabetical order; then in chronological order.
  - Correspondence with contributors, 4 folders
    Some with L. Lorand and Academic Press (carbon copies sent to G.E. Perlmann). Includes refusals to contribute.
    Arranged in alphabetical order.
    - A-E (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - F-K (Box 27, Folder 5)
      Includes Ichisima modified outline.
    - L-O (Box 27, Folder 6)
      Includes S. Moore comments on Elliot and Liu ms. (filed under Liu); Ali comments on Mycek ms.
    - P-Z (Box 27, Folder 7)
      Includes proposed outline for Petra ms; outline of Walsh ms. with additional page proof corrections.
  - New Volume (Tentative) Correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    Correspondents primarily:
    Kim Barsky.
    Sidney Colowick.
    Nathan O. Kaplan.
    Ephraim Katchalski.
    Laszlo Lorand.
    Includes various outlines; working materials. New volume appears to be planned with Ephraim Katchalski; addendum to Vol. XIX with Laszlo Lorand.
  - Contributors and subjects, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    For chapters in 1970 Methods in Enzymology Vol XIX - Proteolytic Enzymes. Alphabetical record on cards.
  - Contributors mss, 7 folders
    Includes photocopy of table of contents and list of contributors from published volume; mss on hand check marked; mss. numbered as to chapter designation in table of contents.
    Arranged in alphabetical order as to contributor.
    - A-C (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - D-I (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - K-L (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - M-N (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - O-R (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - S-Wa (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - We-Z (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Galley Proofs
    Includes working copy of table of contents. Printer's copies with corrections in some instances. In 3 folders. Kept in Chapter order 1-72
    - Chapters 1-11 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Chapters 12-47 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Chapters 48-72 (Box 30, Folder 2)
- Laboratory Notes, 1935-1974
  Notes; looseleaf notebooks. Some literature searches included with laboratory notes; also amino acid analyses. Most folders are subdivided as found and include laboratory procedures and some course and lecture notes attended by G.E. Perlmann.
  Arranged by subject in approximate chronological order. Pages numbered consecutively [by editor].
  - Pacific Grove, Calif. Dr. Van Niels course on "Biochemical aspects of fermentations", 1956 August (Box 31, Folder 1)
    [Pages removed from 4 spiral notebooks and kept in order found].
  - Katchalski lecture notes, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - T. Berlin course notes (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - 1962 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    2 notebooks comprising 3 folders: Perlmann handwritten notes on Uhlenbeck course in Thermodynamics and Statistical Mechanics.
  - Notes by student on Uhlenbeck course in Quantum Mechanics
    Photocopied typed.
    - pp. 1-128 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - pp. 129-239; lacking pp. 165-169 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - M. Kac Holiday Science Lectures (Christmas Lectures) etc., 1962 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Laboratory procedures for students, undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Laboratory procedures, undated (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Laboratory notebooks
    Original covers on loose leaf notebooks removed and pages numbered consecutively. Subject indicated where known.
    - II, 1935 January 21-1939 March 6 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Formoltitration, 1937 April-May (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Metaphosphorsieune II, 1937 May-December 1940 February-March (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Nikotinsi[uneamide?], 1938 February-June (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Nikotinsi[uneamid?] Thiazole, 1938 January-April 1 1938 April 21-June 11 (Box 32, Folder 8)
      Includes 2 notebooks.
    - Croton[siem?] Buttei[sieme?] (Oxyolation), 1938 November-1939 May (Box 32, Folder 9)
      Includes reprint of F. Lipmann abstract.
    - III, 1939 March-April; 1 notebook (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Carlsberg Laboratory, Copenhagen?, 1939? April (Box 32, Folder 11)